Fly
(菅原)こんなのあたんだ
I didn't know we had this!
(清水)頑張れ
You can do it.
(２･３年生たち)うわぁん
(月島)ちょと何これ
Wait, what is this?! This is getting out of hand!
収拾つかないんだけど
(澤村)１回戦絶対勝つぞ
We're going to win in the first round!
(一同)うおす
Yessir!
(田中)百人力だ
う
(澤村)頑張るぞ
(一同)うお
(３人)あ
Morning.
(東峰)なあいよいよ最後の
Listen, it's finally time for...
(２人)しゃべるな
(東峰)はあ
Don't speak!
Pardon?
お前絶対センチメンタルなこと
言うつもりだろ
I'll bet you're about to say something sentimental.
(菅原)｢いよいよ
最後のインタハイだな｣
Like, "it's finally time for our final interhigh..."
とかなんとか
(東峰)え
or other such nonsense.
(東峰)いよいよ
最後のインタハイだな
It's finally time for our final interhigh.
Yeah.
(菅原)俺たち
本当にいろいろあたよな
We've been through a lot together.
That kind of conversation is like
marking us for death, so no way!
そういう会話て
なんか死亡フラグぽいからダメ
Oh, come on! Why not?!
(東峰)なんだよいいじゃんか
昨日だて
最後のインタハイを前に
What about yesterday? I wanted to boost our morale
by getting all us third-years together for a quiet chat under the stars to mentally prepare for our final interhigh.
３年同士で星空を見ながら
静かに語らいつつ
士気を高める的な感じに
なると思てたら
But you guys just up and left.
あさり帰りやがて
(澤村)士気は
清水のサプライズで１２０％だろ
We got a 120% boost in morale thanks to Shimizu's surprise.
(東峰)
うんまあうんそうだけど
Yeah, well...
Yeah, true, but...
(菅原)俺たちは今日
１回戦も２回戦も勝て
Miyagi Prefectural Karasuno Senior High School
Today we have to win in the first and second round to make it to day two.
２日目に進むんだから
I don't want to talk like it's all over just yet.
今しんみりした話なんか
しなくていい
目の前の試合全部勝つ
We'll win every match put in front of us!
今はそんだけ考える
おお
That's all you need to think about!
Right.
(澤村)
頼りにしてんだからなエス
Because we're counting on you, ace.
(東峰)おお
大地が優しいとなんか怖いな
Sure.
Daichi is kind of scary when he's being nice.
(菅原)なんか降るかもな
Maybe it'll rain.
(澤村)じゃあ
厳しくしといた方がいいかな
Would you prefer me to rake you over the coals instead?
≪(日向翔陽)はざます
≪(影山飛雄)おはようございます
Good morning!
ははは
(澤村)おう今部室開ける
Right! We'll open up the clubroom now!
(澤村)行くぞ
(菅原･東峰)おう
Let's go.
Right!
Episode Fifteen:
We're Back
(渋谷)
烏野てどんなヤツらかなぁ
I wonder what the Karasuno team is like.
あんまり
でかいのいないといいなぁ
I hope they aren't too tall.
Don't worry. They say that they haven't been that hot recently.
(茶屋)大丈夫だて最近は
大したことないて話じゃん
≫(他校生)
もう白鳥沢の一人勝ちだろ
Shiratorizawa will take the whole thing as usual.
いや今年は
青葉城西がヤバいらしいよ
No, Aoba Jousai seems to be a threat this year.
及川が３年になてから
頭一つ抜けてるて
They're a cut above the rest now that Oikawa is a third-year.
And I hear the Seijou first-years are improving fast.
あと１年の伸びが
すげぇんだてさ青城は
いやつても
伊達工ブロクには
But can they win in a block with Date Tech?
勝てないんじゃないの
Ａブロク入んなくてよかた
I'm glad we aren't in Block A.
えとあそこのブロクは
Let's see, Block A has...
Karasuno
(他校生)とり鳥野
(他校生)｢烏野｣じゃね
Tori? Torino?
Don't you mean Karasuno?
ちょと前まで
強かたとこじゃん
Weren't they pretty good a few years back?
Yeah, maybe a few years ago.
(他校生)
ああちょと前まではね
今はなんかね
ダサい異名が付いてんだよ
Now they've earned themselves a totally lame nickname.
(他校生)えどんな
(他校生)確か
Really? What is it?
If I remember correctly, "the fallen champs."
堕ちた強豪飛べない烏
"The clipped crows."
Hey, be careful!
おいちょヤバいて
ん
Huh?
Can't fly? What's that again? Hmm?
(田中)
飛べないなんですてん
(澤村)こら行くぞすみません
(他校生)あいえ
Come on, we're going!
I'm so sorry.
That's okay.
Stop picking fights.
すぐ絡まない
(田中)はい
Yes, sir.
(他校生)なんか黒い
They look so dark.
(他校生)高校生に見えないヤツ
交じてねぇ
One of them doesn't look like he belongs in high school.
ああれはまさか
烏野の東峰
I-Is that who I think it is?!
It's Azumane of Karasuno!
What? Who's he?
え何誰
知らねぇのかよ
You mean you don't know?!
北高のヤツを手下に使て
ボコらしてたとか
I heard he got his underlings to
beat up the guys from North High.
(東峰)おらお前もやれよ
Come on, join in.
(東峰･((ケンカだ
警察警察呼びましょう
It's a fight! I have to call the police!
(他校生)路上でなんか
ヤバいもん売りつけてたとか
And he tried to sell a questionable substance on the street.
５万でいいよ
50,000 works for me.
You dropped your handkerchief.
((ハンカチ落としましたよ))
((すみません
I'm sorry!
(他校生)５年留年してるんだて
(他校生)はあ成人じゃん
And he got held back five years.
What?! Then he's an adult!
まあまあいつものことじゃん
見た目がそんなんだからだろ
There, there. It's just the norm.
That's the image you project.
(東峰)お俺はなんかこう
All I wanted...
was to look a little wild on the outside, that's all!
外見からでもワイルドな感じに
なりたいと思て
(菅原)ほらもう
そんなこと言うところが
There, y'see? Nobody wild would go around saying that.
ワイルドじゃないもん
(東峰)う
(西谷)はははは
いいじゃないすか
What's wrong with that? Who cares what you look like?
どう見られるかなんて
This is what we call "wild."
(澤村･菅原)
こういうのをワイルドと言う
(西谷)ん
≫(他校生)おいあれ見ろ
Hey, look at that.
(武田)横断幕効いたみたいだね
そうですか
It looks like the banner did its job!
Do you think so?
僕のポエムなんかより
よぽど効果あたよ
It was far more effective than my silly poem.
掛けてみろよ
She's cute!
Go talk to her.
Should I? Should I really?
行ちゃう行てみちゃう
(田中)ガルルルガルルル
(西谷)シャシャ
(清水)やめなさい
Knock that off.
Kiyoko...
(田中)潔子さんに
(西谷)はたかれた
...smacked me!
Say, you see the little guy?
(他校生)なああの小さいヤツて
千鳥山の西谷だよな
That's gotta be Nishinoya from Chidoriyama.
中総体でベストリベロ賞取てた
今日も一日頑張れる
He won the award for best libero in junior high.
Now I have the energy for another day!
What, he did?
えそうなの
それだけじゃない
That's not all.
あれてあれだろ
天才セタて噂の
Look at him over there.
He's that prodigy setter they're talking about.
(他校生)
北川第一のコト上の王様
Kitagawa First's King of the Court!
Huh?
ああふん
(他校生)なんで烏野
(他校生)さあ
Why Karasuno?
Beats me.
But he had a really bad rep in junior high.
でもあいつ中学んとき
あんま評判よくなかたよな
じゃあさあいつは
Okay, then who's he?
あの小さいヤツも
なんかすごいヤツ
Is the little guy as impressive as the rest of them?
Whoa!
うわはは
いやあれは
ちょと知らない
Actually, I...
have no idea.
おお人がいぱいだ
Ooh! Look at all the people!
The
Top
あ俺も
The
Top
I'm the same!
俺もてぺん目指します
I'm also aiming for the top! I won't be beaten!
負けません
ははあ
Oh.
You idiot! What're you doing?!
(菅原)バカ何やてんだ
あすいませんすいません
I'm so sorry.
いえ
あ
That's okay.
体育館でけぇ
This gymnasium is huge!
I can smell the Air Salonpas!
エアサロンパスのにおい
何言てんだお前
What're you talking about?
このにおいて
大会て感じすんだよ
This smell makes a tournament feel real.
I get you, bro!
(西谷)分かる
≫(他校生)あ来た
They're here!
Yikes, they're huge!
≫(他校生)げでか
(一同)ん
Date Tech
(他校生)伊達工業だ
It's Date Tech!
No eyebrows!
≪眉毛もない
(西谷)なんだてめぇあ
Who do you think you are?
(茂庭)ちょ
ちょいちょいちょいちょい
Hold it, hold it, hold it.
Stop that!
やめなさい
すみませんすみません
I'm so sorry!
(澤村)いえ
(茂庭)おい二口手伝え
That's okay.
Hey, Futakuchi. Give me a hand.
(二口)
はいすみませんこいつ
Coming!
I'm so sorry. The dude has a habit of singling out a team's ace.
エスと分かると
ロクオンする癖があて
だから
So I'd like you to get good and ready...
今回も覚悟しといてくださいね
to lose again.
(茂庭)お前ら失礼すぎだろ
You guys are way too rude!
Why do you always do that?!
なんで
いつもそういうことするんだよ
(菅原)いや
ちょとびくりしたなぁ
Well, that was a little scary.
(澤村)ああ
(菅原)よく目ぇそらさなかたな
Yeah.
I'm amazed you kept looking him in the eye.
(東峰)き緊張した
Th-That was nerve-wracking.
Why are you such a wimp off the court?
(西谷)なんでコトの外だと
そんなに弱いんですか
Noya, sugarcoat it!
(田中)ノヤさんオブラト
≫(池尻)澤村
ん
Sawamura.
久しぶり
(澤村)おお池尻
Long time no see.
Hey, Ikejiri!
Go on ahead without me, guys.
すまんちょい先行てて
(一同)うす
Yessir.
(澤村)ほんと久しぶりだな
(池尻)なんかでかくなたな
It's really been a long time.
You look bigger somehow.
(澤村)
そうか身長同じくらいだろ
Really? I'm the same height as I was before.
いやそうじゃなくて
That's not what I meant.
I'm bigger sideways?!
横にか
違うて
Not that.
(池尻)
≪ガタイが違う気迫が違う
His build has changed, his intensity has changed, and I'll bet his training schedule has changed too.
たぶん練習量も違う≫
さき
入り口で見かけたんだけど
I saw you at the entrance a second ago,
but you were so intimidating, I couldn't say anything.
掛けられなかた
What the heck?
なんだよそれ
まあうちの連中
Yeah, we do have a few outwardly intimidating guys in our crew.
見た目だけ迫力あるヤツ
多いからなぁ
No, they look really tough.
いやすげぇ強そうだよ
澤村も
そうか
And so do you.
You think?
Anyway, we're what you call a small-time team.
(池尻)まあ
うちはいわゆる弱小校だから
池尻
(池尻)今の発言取り消し
Ikejiri?
I take that back!
It doesn't matter if we're small time or big time, or former big time!
弱小校とか強豪とか
元強豪とか関係ない
If a net stands between us, we'll wipe the floor with you!
ネト挟むからには
けちょんけちょんにしてやかんな
(アヤ)緊張してきた
(烏野女子)ですね
I'm getting nervous.
Yeah.
(アヤ)なんかさきの練習で
相手のスパイクすごくなかた
Was it me, or were our opponent's spikes really amazing at practice?
They made it to the round of 8 last year.
去年のベスト８ですもんね
私のところに来ませんように
I hope we don't get matched against them!
もとちゃんと
朝練出とけばよかたな
Maybe we should've been more diligent about morning practice.
(澤村)((もしも
相手が絶対かなわないような
Even if you find yourself facing an unbeatably tough opponent,
強敵だとしても
勝とうとしなきゃ勝てないよ))
you can't win unless you try.
(道宮)今から思うと
いぱい時間あたよな
Looking back at it now, we had more than enough time.
もともと
練習できたのかもしれない
We could've practiced more than we did.
やるべきことが
あたかもしれない
Maybe we should've given it more priority.
Yui, it's too late.
結今はそんな
でももうそんなの関係ない
But none of that matters anymore!
あと４５分で
試合開始の笛が鳴る
The starting whistle blows in 45 minutes.
All we can do now is do a proper warmup and
play to the best of our ability until the very end!
今私たちができるのは
ｳｫｰﾐﾝｸﾞｱｯﾌﾟをしかりやて
最後まで精一杯戦うこと
そして勝とうよ
After that...
we need to win!
みんな集まて円陣組もう
Everyone gather 'round!
Huddle up!
ほらみんなも
(一同)ええ
C'mon, that means you too!
What?
(道宮)烏野ファイ
Karasuno, fight!
Yeah!
Hey, don't tell me your stomach is hurting again.
おいまた腹が痛いとか
言うんじゃないだろうな
むむひゃうるいだ
なんだて
I-I'm quivering in ancipation!
Excuse me?!
I think he's "quivering in anticipation."
(菅原)
武者震いて言たんじゃない
Nah. He's just quivering, period.
(田中)
いや普通に震えてるだけだろ
I get it! The sight of Date Tech freaked you out!
(西谷)あれか
さきの伊達工見てビビたか
Of course it did—I mean didn't—I mean did!
そそんなわけ
ないじゃないじゃないですか
Make up your mind!
(田中)どちだ
≪くそまたのまれてる≫
Shit. He's being overwhelmed again.
≪早いとこなんとかしないと
We've got to do something quick,
or it'll be the match against Seijou all over again.
≪あの青城戦の二の舞だけは
まずい≫
(菅原)同じ小心者でも
旭はあんま緊張しないよな
You're just as wimpy, but you
don't look that nervous, Asahi.
Wimpy?
(東峰)小心者とか
緊張を紛らわすコツがあるんだよ
There's a trick to get rid of the jitters.
今まで最凶に怖かたことを
思い出すんだ
Recall an experience that scared the living daylights out of you.
それが怖ければ怖いほど
｢これから起こることは
The scarier the better.
It'll remind you that there are scarier things out there, so you can handle this.
それより怖いはずがない平気｣
てなるから
≪今までで最凶に怖かたこと≫
Something that scared the living daylights out of me?
≪うんうんんん
あ
(菅原)ん日向
Hinata?
Hey, I think I'm okay now.
あもう大丈夫です
おい日向どうした
Hinata, what's wrong?!
対処法分かてんのに
なんで伊達工と戦たとき
If you had a coping strategy, why did you get so bummed the last time we took on Date Tech?
あんなにへこんだんですか
(東峰)う
Noya, stop pouring salt and pepper into his wounds like that.
(田中)またノヤさんは
そうやて傷口に塩こしょうを
I had no time to daydream like that.
そういう妄想する余裕がなくて
It takes time and concentration and other conditions to daydream!
妄想するにも
時間とか集中力とか
いろいろ必要なんだて
めんどくさ
Too much work.
(澤村)よし準備はいいか
Okay, are you ready?
第１試合だ
そろそろアプ取るぞ
It's our first match! We need to warm up.
Yes, sir!
Finally, an official match!
≪いよいよ公式戦だ≫
Haikyuu !!
Aspire to Go Forward
It's so spacious!
広いでかい
It's so huge!
Hey, no freaking out.
おいビビてんじゃねぇぞ
ぬおめぇだよ
You're the freak.
どう見てもおめぇだよ
そそんなに怒んなよ
You're the only freak here!
D-Don't get so mad at me!
あ
ああ
Fly
(繋心)
よしじゃあ練習始めんぞ
All righty, then! Let's start practice!
Yessir!
(入畑)
もう一回見ておかないとな
We need another look at them.
烏野１年生コンビの
あの強烈な速攻
I want to see the Karasuno first-year duo's fast attack.
Yes, sir.
青葉城西だ
でけぇやぱ強そうだな
It's Aoba Jousai.
They're tall.
They really do look tough.
その中でもこのチムといえば
セタの
The one who's most central to their team is their setter...
あれいない
Hey, I don't see him.
(入畑)ん及川どうした
Where is Oikawa?
(矢巾)えええと
(溝口)なんだ早く言え
W-Well...
Come on, out with it.
(矢巾)
外で他校の女子に捕まてます
He's been held up outside by girls from other schools.
He's amazing!
He's so cool!
岩泉
(岩泉)はい
Iwaizumi.
Yes, sir.
(及川)
うんあこれおいしい
Hey, these are good! Did you really make them yourself?
ほんとに手作り
はい
Yes! I stayed up late last night to make them!
昨日夜更かしして作りました
(及川)うわうれしい
Wow, that's awesome! Thanks!
ありがとう
いえそんな
It was nothing, really!
Oikawa, can I please take a photo with you?
及川さん
あの一緒に写真いいですか
え写真もちろんいい
What, a photo? But of course!
ガン
(一同)うわ
Oikawa?
お及川さん
(及川)いた
Ow! I've never been hit before, even by my coach!
監督にも
ぶたれたことないのにん
(及川)ごめん写真はまた今度ね
(一同)ええ
Sorry, we'll take that photo another time.
Aw...
あらきょヘド
(国見)ぷ
Hey! It's turnip head!
(金田一)
らきょヘドてなんだ
What's a "turnip head"?
You are. Who else could it be?
(国見)お前以外に誰がいる
は
Wha?
と
(及川)やほ
And...
Yoo-hoo!
飛雄ちゃんチビちゃん
元気に変人コンビやてる
Tobio and Small Fry.
Having fun with your deviant combination?
大王様
痛
Great King!
Ow!
That hurt, Iwa.
痛いよ岩ちゃんあれ
Huh?
リベロがいるねぇ
練習試合のときはいなかたのに
You have a libero now.
Gimme another ball!
You didn't when we had our practice match.
(岩泉)
なんかでかいヤツも増えてんな
They seem to have more big guys now too.
Please pass me another ball!
What's this?
おや
それと
They also have a new instructor, I think.
新しい指導者ですかね
Hey, we have a limited amount of time, so keep hitting those!
日向オドオドすんな
うひぃ
Hinata, pick up your feet!
New players and a new instructor.
新しい選手に指導者か
How has Karasuno changed?
どんなふうに変わたかな
烏野は
(武田)はぁいよいよですね
It's finally happening.
こんな広くて
大勢の人たちがいる場所で
Our team is going to play in this enormous, packed venue.
みんなは戦うんですね
I think I'm getting nervous just looking at this.
なんだか見ている
こちの方が緊張します
だからこそ
That's precisely why...
僕たちは僕たちができることを
we need to do what we can, to the best of our ability.
精一杯やりましょう
(清水)はい
Yes, sir.
(二口)せのく
One, two...
行きます
≪伊達工
I'm going!
Date Tech.
(西谷)旭さん
あ
Asahi!
俺も伊達工すげぇ気になります
負けるつもりはないです
Date Tech seriously worries me too.
I have no intention of losing.
I'm only thinking of winning. That's precisely why...
勝つことだけ考えてます
だからこそ
今は目の前の相手に
集中しましょう
we need to focus on the opponent in front of us.
Right.
ああ
Captains!
キャプテン
(澤村)よろしくお願いします
(駒木)よよろしくお願いします
Let's have a good match.
Together we can make the flowers of effort bloom
集合整列
Gather 'round!
Form a line!
ドクンドクン(鼓動)
ドクンドクン
ドクン
(一同)お願いします
Let's have a good match!
ゴゴレツゴ
レツゴ伊達工
Go, go, let's go! Let's go, Date Tech!
The Iron Wall of Date
うわ
(伊達工応援団)ﾚｯﾂｺﾞｰ伊達工
ゴゴレツゴ
レツゴ伊達工
(繋心)いいか開幕１戦目
Now listen! This is the first match of the tournament.
誰だて緊張なり高揚なりで
ふだんどおりじゃない
This would make anyone nervous enough to throw off their game!
そこから
いかに一歩早く抜け出るかだ
Our challenge is to shake it off before they do.
まずは一本ドカと決めて
We need to start by scoring one point to get into the rhythm!
流れをつかめ
(一同)おす
Yessir!
What I'm about to say is neither flattery nor loyalty.
(武田)これは
お世辞でも親バカでもなくて
みんなは強いです
烏野は強いです
You're all good.
Karasuno has a good team!
Let's show the entire stadium that
"the clipped crows" can fly once again!
飛べない烏がまた飛ぶところ
会場中に見せてあげましょう
(西谷)
うお武ちゃん名ゼリフきた
Whoa! Take's brought out the buzzwords!
(田中)相変わらず
今回も言われてるもんなぁ
I'll bet anything they're saying that infamous nickname right now.
あの不名誉な異名
(他校生)
((堕ちた強豪飛べない烏))
"The fallen champs, the clipped crows."
And then we'll say to them...
そして言てやるのです
｢見よ古兵烏野の復活だ｣と
Observe! The old warhorse, Karasuno, is back!
Yessir!
(武田)は
ポエミだた引いた
Was it too poetic?! Did it gross you out?!
It's okay! Don't worry!
(澤村)大丈夫です大丈夫
｢ふるつわもの｣て何
What's an old warhorse?
You think I know?
俺に分かると思うのか
(菅原)正確には違うけど
It's not strictly accurate, but it basically implies "We were strong once."
｢昔は強かた｣的なニュアンスで
(澤村)おいもう行くぞ
Hey! We're going!
烏野ファイ
Karasuno, fight!
Yessir!
(一同)おおす
(監督)
落ち着いてまずは一本だ
Calm down and get that first point.
It's okay. The time we spent training won't let us down!
大丈夫
やてきた練習は裏切らない
Make your receiving skills count.
とにかくレシブ繋いでいこう
(一同)おす
Yessir!
(玉川)ええあの10番て
ミドルブロカなの
What the heck? Is that number ten their middle blocker?
どう見ても
１６０センチくらいだよな
He can't be more than 160 cm.
(芳賀)ベンチに
もとでかいヤツいるのに
They have taller guys on the bench.
(岩泉)ははは
相手戸惑てんなぁ
Their opponent is confused.
まあ当然だよな
Which is only natural.
Who'd put him up for middle blocker where you fight for height?
高さ勝負のミドルブロカに
あれだもんな
Is that tiny number ten really a starter?
あの小さい１０番スタメンなの
リベロじゃないんだ
He isn't a libero.
Those who mock will pay the piper.
なめたヤツは痛い目見ます
ははは経験者は語る
Spoken like an expert!
次は絶対ねじ伏せてみせます
I'll force him into submission next time.
さ来い
(池尻)駒木ナイサ
Now, bring it!
Komaki, give us a nice serve!
旭
(東峰)オライ
Asahi!
Got it!
It's our first shot.
≪一発目誰を使う
Nice receive!
Who do I use?
≪相手をビビらしかつ
こちの士気を上げる
Who will spook our opponent and boost our morale?
≪一発目はやぱしこの人
The first shot has to be his!
Yo, heave-ho!
わせら
ふん
ピ
(２人)うおお
うわ
ナイス田中
うおら
Nice, Tanaka.
Take that!
いい出だし
うわぁ
It's a good start.
Knock it off already!
うるさい長い
ピピ
はは烏野もう注意されてる
早バカだなぁ
Karasuno already got a warning!
That was fast. Boy, they're dumb.
(駒木)大丈夫大丈夫
切り替えて取り返すぞ
It's okay! Let's switch gears and give it back to them!
(芳賀)落ち着いて
一本取り返してこ
Be calm and take back that point!
ピ
(澤村)田中ナイサ
Tanaka, give us a good one!
It's that cueball!
(他校生)さきの坊主だ
(桜井)オケ
Okay.
Nice receive!
(玉川)ナイスレシブ
(芳賀)池尻さん
Ikejiri!
Whoa, he dug it out!
(他校生)うわすげぇ拾た
(他校生)あのリベロ反応速ぇ
That libero has fast reflexes!
Shit, it didn't go back to our setter!
≪くそセタに返てねぇ≫
Asahi!
旭
(池尻)レフト来るぞ３枚つけ
The left wing spiker is coming! Triple up!
頼むぜエス
We're counting on you, ace!
(観客たち)うお
(他校生)すげさすが成人
Wow! That's a grown man for you!
(他校生)
５年留年してんだてよ
I hear he was held back five years!
For real?! Is that allowed?
(他校生)マジそれいいの
(他校生)偽てんじゃね
Maybe he lies about his age.
Asahi, pull it together!
旭気をしかり
Whoa, that had some real power to it.
(岩泉)うおすげぇ威力だな
(金田一)はい
Yes.
(繋心)
見たかうちのレフトのパワ
Did you witness the power of our left wing spiker?
でも
うちの武器はそれだけじゃねぇぞ
But we have many more weapons up our sleeves.
うるせぇ分かてんだよ
ピ
Shut up! I know!
(澤村)
田中もう一本ナイサ
Tanaka, do another one of those!
I got it!
(玉川)オライ
((みんなは強いです
烏野は強いです))
You're all good.
Karasuno has a good team!
(武田)
((飛べない烏がまた飛ぶところ
Let's show the entire stadium...
会場中に見せてあげましょう
"the clipped crows" can fly once again!
飛んだ
He's flying.
Observe.
(武田)見よ古兵
Fly
The old warhorse...
(武田)烏野の復活だ
Karasuno, is back!
Next Episode Preview
We've been waiting for this!
いよ待てました
You do not know, so I shall tell you now.
(田中)
知らざあ言て聞かせやしょう
Here in Sendai, Miyagi prefecture, when anyone speaks of Karasuno, the old warhorse...
(西谷)ここぞ宮城の仙台で
(田中)古兵の烏野たぁ
(田中･西谷)俺らのことだぁ
they mean us!
Next time on Haikyuu!!:
Episode Sixteen:
Winner and Loser
"Winner and Loser."